Senior Front-End Developer & Accessibility specialist

t: 022 093 5725 | e: fedbysandrine@gmail.com | w: fedbysandrine.com

SKILLS

Semantic HTML
WCAG 2.1 / 2.2
WAI-ARIA
Screen readers
CSS methodologies
Responsive design
UI/UX best practices
JS DOM manipulation
CMS, PHP templating
SVN versioning
Dev Tools console

INTERESTS

Usability
Design systems
Web vitals
Web components
Green web
Scalable modern CSS
Dev flow automation
Indie web

React & JS frameworks

REFERENCES

GLENN WRIGHT

Former technical director at Digital Arts Network t: 021 392 600

e: glenn.wright@goboxer.com

CHANDRA HARRISON

Director at Access Advisors

t: 027 395 8870

e: chandra.harrison@accessadvisors.nz

PROFILE

For the past two decades, I have focused my efforts on interface development, putting user advocacy at the forefront, and providing a pleasant user experience for people with disabilities.

My purpose is to bring my knowledge and experience to teams and projects where I can have a meaningful impact.

WORK EXPERIENCES

SEPT 2020 - CURRENT

Freelance at FEDbySandrine, Auckland, NZ

- o Supported agency team on over a dozen of projects integrating designs, resolving issues, adding updates, and upgrading boilerplate starter.
- o Developed an interactive touch-screen experience for a museum exhibition
- o Reviewed and strategised UX for better conversion of a SASS

Accessibility specialist, contract at Access Advisors, Christchurch, NZ

- o Audit websites, apps, mockups, designs, and various user experiences from digital to the real world
- o Provide WCAG assessments with descriptive issue impact and how to fix them
- o Advise design and developer teams during project conception
- o Research and write white papers, presentations, and a developer training course
- o Peer review and mentor team members on technical details

Sandrine not only has extensive knowledge about digital accessibility, but also a way of imparting that knowledge that is clear and concise.

Trent Morgan, Web Developer at Big Fish Creative

MAY 2015 - AUG 2020

Digital Arts Network, Auckland, NZ

- Led the front-end of Tourism New Zealand website
- Worked closely with designers to create new components, templates, campaigns, and refactoring UI
- Evolved existing UI into a design system with components library and documentation of coding conventions
- Reported, advised, and implement UX and coding strategies for consistency and sustainability.
- o Assessed and resolved legacy code and responsive issues
- Worked closely with back-end developers to prototype and implement new features ('near me' map, 360 videos campaign, mobile mega nav menu, ...)

Sandrine brings a level of excellence through her craft and dedication to standards and good practice. Her diligence and commitment to the quality of her outputs ensures the quality never slips.

Glenn Wright, Technical Director at Digital Arts Network

AUG 2011 - MAY 2015

Freelance, Worldwide

Senior Front-End Developer & Accessibility specialist

t: 022 093 5725 | e: fedbysandrine@gmail.com | w: fedbysandrine.com

EDUCATION

2005 – 2006 Technical Bachelor Degree, Online Digital Design and Development

LES GOBELINS,

PARIS 8 UNIVERSITY, FRANCE

LANGUAGES

English French

SOCIAL

Former co-organiser and speaker at Auckland CSS Meetup

sandrinepns on:

linkedin.com

@fedbysandrine on:

mastodon.social instagram.com twitter.com codepen.io github.com

STATUS

NZ permanent resident

WORK EXPERIENCES CONTINUED

AUG 2011 - MAY 2015

Freelance, Worldwide

JUNE 2011 - NOV 2011

Orchard Marketing, Sydney, Australia

- In charge of front-end development, maintenance, and accuracy of several websites with common and shared structure
- o Front-end integration, update, and maintenance of EDM, event micro-website and promotions
- o Updated ASP elements to output proper semantic
- o Resolved CSS design and cross-browsing conflicts to support older browsers

AUG 2009 - APR 2011

Pixelfusion, Auckland, NZ

- o Advised during design process on user experiences and interfaces
- Provided HTML SE optimized, from efficient HTML for emailing to semantic HTML5
- o Resolved CSS design and cross-browsing conflicts to support older browsers with graceful degradation strategy
- Development unobtrusive DOM manipulation scripts
- Developed PHP Symfony templates, and worked closely with developer team to design databases

AUG 2008 – AUG 2009

Shift, Auckland, NZ

- o Front-end development HTML/CSS/JS, SEO, cross-browsing issues resolving
- o CMS implementation HTML/PHP (Expression engine)
- o PHP development

JULY 2006 - APR 2008

TBWA, Paris, France

- Lead front-end and brought it as part of the design process
- o Introduced tableless integration, good practices for eDM, HTML, CSS and cross-browser compatibility
- Developed cohesive team work with managers, designers, back-end developers, providers, and freelancers

JULY 2005 – JUNE 2006

Les Artisans Numériques, Paris, France

- o Developed dashboards, websites, and newsletters
- o Introduced table-less integration and good practices for SEO

SEPT 2004 – JUNE 2005

Etudium, Lorient, France

- o Maintained and optimized website and dashboard
- o Proposed, prototyped, and developed custom PHP solutions for easier management of clients and products.